

EDUCATION

PGCE iQTS (2022-2023) University of Birmingham

MBA (2000-2002) IIMM, Pune, 1st Div.

BSc. Hons. Botany (1996-99) Delhi University ,1st Div.

CONTACT

+971 557173590 shwetasinghg10@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/shwetasingh-b4a7813/ Jebel Ali, Dubai

SKILLS

Quick Learner Empathetic Compassionate

Confident Communicator Risk Taker

Digital Savvy
Driven & Perseverance

Business Acumen Connecting the Dots

SHWETA SINGH

Corporate business professional turned into an educationist to give back to community by facilitating children's learning to develop them into compassionate citizens of the world.

PROFILE

Management Professional with 15 years' experience in HR Industry. Transitioned to be an Educationist with a UK certified PGCE iQTS from University of Birmingham and with a passion of counselling professionals & students to make right career choices. Have been trained in British Overseas Schools in Dubai. Confident of deploying my client managing, counselling & teaching skills in an Educationist role for the benefit of a school community. Believe in being respectful & trustworthy, representing the institutions' ethos with utmost sincerity and keeping the best interest of the learners at the core.

WORK EXPERIENCE

THE ARBOR SCHOOL, Dubai – Trainee Teacher

JAN 2023-MAY 2023

- Managing multicultural students in Year 6 as a homeroom teacher teaching Maths, English, Science & PosEd.
- Creating & Planning Lessons, making cross curriculum connections, deploying questionings & assessment techniques.
- Participating in year group meetings to discuss curriculum planning, deploying adaptive teaching & scaffolding.
- Engaging students through focused instructional strategies, audio visual aids & hands-on activities
- Creating WAGOLLs & assessment tasks suited for differentiated learners, marking notebooks, guiding peer assessments.
- Supporting The Arbor Singers Program as part of ECA.

REGENT INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL, Dubai – Trainee Teacher OCT 2022–JAN 2023

- Managed multi-cultural students of Year 4 as a homeroom teacher teaching English, Maths, Science & VIA.
- Managed the classroom by applying rules & routines, positive behaviour reinforcement and supported EALs & Low attainers.
- Planned and delivered English Grammar lessons on commas, apostrophe, suffix, paragraph writing and Poem analysis.
- Prepared the Assessment BSG tasks for students of varied attainment levels.
- Built relationships with Students & **SEND child** based on mutual trust and supervised them for the school trips.

TEACHING PHILOSOPHY

"A Teacher needs to go beyond the curriculum to ignite the spark of Knowledge, Creativity & compassion in children and be open to learning to embark upon +a more meaningful, engaging, and purposeful teaching journey."

CERTIFICATIONS

Managerial Leadership & Conflict Resolution, IIM - Calcutta, 2008

CEI Basic, NTUC Learning Hub Singapore, 2011

German Basic Level A1.1 Goethe Institute Singapore ,2011

16 PF Psychometric Testing PSL, UK, 2005

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Singing Poetry Drama Travelling Badminton

PERSONAL VITAE

DOB - 30/09/1979 Marital Status - Married

Husband -Director, Swiss FMCG Children -One Daughter ,9 yrs

Languages – English, Hindi, Bengali, Punjabi, Urdu, German

CORPORATE WORK HISTORY

CIEL HR (Ma Foi Group) Delhi – General Manager June 2019-Jun 2020

AETOS Consulting (CIEL Franchisee), Dubai – General Manager Sept 2016 - 2019

ARTEMIS HR & NASTRAC Singapore - Head - Biz Dev.

Jun 2011 - Nov 2012

MA FOI RANDSTAD, India – Senior Manager – Biz Dev.

Sept 2004 - Mar 2011

AVESTHAGEN, Bangalore – Mgmt Trainee

May 2002 - Aug 2004

indislan

INDISTAN, Dubai – Founder Jan 2013 onwards

MANAGEMENT EXPERIENCES

Have consistently **delivered results through initiative taking**, deploying **new ideas & strategies** and **perseverance** in setting up **business units from early stages**, throughout my career.

- Food & GMO testing Unit Bangalore & Hyderabad
- Branch Unit Business Chennai, Delhi & Pune
- Staffing Business in Public sector in Delhi & NCR
- Setting up IT&TS Recruitment Business in Singapore,
- Launching Indistan & Aetos (CIEL franchise) in Dubai

Have been passionate about offering the best recruitment solutions to the clients for their expansion plans and counselling candidates to make the right career choices.

Have mentored management trainees and my team members through workshops, Institutional meets, and training sessions.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- I have been recognized and promoted to take up new challenges throughout my stints in the corporate sector.
- Have been awarded Service Excellence award by Ma Foi
- Have been felicitated by **Randstad Management for** winning **RFP bids** from prestigious PSU clients.
- Have been awarded for best team player for setting up Avesthagen stall at Bangalore Bio 2003.
- Have been empaneled with Dubai based Smart Life Foundation as English Teacher teaching blue-collar workers since 2017.
- Have successfully completed Vedic Studies course from ISKCON Vrindayan